now in this lesson
we're going to calculate the surface
area
of a cube
now what's the formula for that
how can we calculate the surface area
of a cube
so all sides of a cube are the same
now let's say if you want to calculate
the area of one of the six faces
let's say the area of this face
it's going to be the length
times the width
now both the length of the width is
equal to x
so if the area of one face is x times x
or x squared
and each face is the same the area or
the total surface area of all six faces
is six x squared
and so let's say if
the side length of a cube is
eight centimeters
the surface area
is going to be six times eight
centimeters squared
eight squared is 64
and six times 64
is
384 and it's going to be square
centimeters
so that's how you can calculate the
surface area
of a cube it's 6x squared where x is the
side length of the cube
you